Hi, welcome.
Today we are going to talk about how
to reduce AI agents costs and mistake
with semantic tool selection Every
time your agent calls the model,
it packs the description for all il
tools, its tools into the context.
If you have 29 tools, every time that
you invoke your agent, the agent is going
to send in, into the model all the 29
tool description inside that invocation.
And if your agent have memory, its
information is going to accumulate
inside the memory and your context
inside your context window is
going to be bigger, and bigger.
And doesn't matter if you only
need to answer a simple question.
It's going to have all the content for
all the tools inside that invocation.
And that's it, thousand of tokens on
every single query that you have to pay.
And the bill is going to be bigger
and bigger in each invocation.
And that's not all the problem.
So there is a second problem that you
have there because the more similar tools
it has, the more it picks the wrong one.
So it can hallucinate the
tools for answer the question.
And today, we fix both with a simple
Jupyter Notebook when we are going to
measure accuracy and tokens on real runs.
And my name is Elizabeth Fuentes.
I am a developer advocate at AWS,
and this talk that we are talking
here about is a, is inside of a seri-
series that I call Stop A- Agent from
Failing or Stop Agent Hallucination.
And this is the second
part for this series.
I'm going to share with you all the code.
If you are interesting in the
other techniques, you are going
to have that techniques as well.
And today, we are going to talk
about semantic tool selection, and
all the code is open source, is
open, I will share that with you.
So let's start.
So the dual problem I just
mentioned is tokens and wrong tool.
If you have token waste because you
have to send all the tools information
in each invoke, and you need to pay for
whatever are you using that tool or not.
And- The cost growth with each tool added.
And the other problem is wrong tool
selection because gener- if you
are building super generic tool
description, the model start to
hallucinate more because it can be a
little complicated between that generic
eh, description inside the tool,
and more tools means more confusion.
And if your engine choose the wrong
tool, it become a wrong answer Here
is the agent that the application
that we are going to build today.
So we are going to have
a query, of course.
Then we are going to send that query
to a face search vector store here
locally in my Jupyter Notebook.
So that we are going to search that
query inside that the vector store.
The vector store is going to have
all tools by name and description,
and this vector store is going to
retrieve, is going to return the
only the top three tools that we are
going to use to answer the question.
For example, here we have
how much is the Mario cost?
How much?
So we send that query, and then the
vector store is going to retrieve
for us pricing details and compare,
and we are going to send that only
three tools for our LLM as a context.
So the LLM is going to use that
tools to answer the question
And here is the thing.
I love this image.
So we have traditional versus
semantic tool dis-discovery.
Before, without semantic tool discovery,
you need to spend for each tokens,
and now with this, you spend less
token, and the difference is almost
eighty-five percent favor tokens.
I mentioned that here.
So let's start with the demo part
Here, this is the code I
am going to share with you.
And let me see.
So let me open this.
So here, you are- I'm going to share
with you all the techniques, and the
sixth one is how you can put all this
technique in production using AEn Core.
Amazon AEn Core is a service that we have
dedicated only to agentic application.
But this is not a talk about it.
If you want to learn more,
everything is there in that code.
And here is the thing that matters
today, search semantic tool.
So I'm going to close this.
And first, we need to
install the requirements.
In this talk, I'm using a
Trance agent as a framework.
Trance
agent is a framework, as is a SDK.
It's completely open source that we
we, in AWS, we are the maintainer.
So this framework is open source.
Repeat, I'm going to repeat that
it's open source, so it's completely
free and it's model agnostic.
You can use this framework
with Amazon Bedrock, Gemini
Anthropy, Ollama locally as well.
And what else I can tell
you about this framework?
It build the agentic loop with a
single line, so it's super simple
to use, and I'm going to show that.
So because this is model
agnostic, I'm going to use this.
I am going to build my agent using
OpenAI, so I need to import my AP key.
So here is my Trance.
I import Trance, and I'm using agent.
And because I'm going to use OpenAI as a
model provider, I need to import OpenAI.
And I'm going to have a bunch of
dummy tools, 29 tools, that I'm going
to use, let me show you here, that
I'm going to put inside my agent.
So I have search real
hotel, get the hotel.
So this is a bunch of dummy
tools with a simple description,
so they are not the best tool.
And let me run this.
And of course, I have some applications
or little tools that I built that
I'm going to use as a helper.
So because I'm using a files, I
need something to build my index.
I have all the there, and something
to search inside my index.
And this swap tools, we are
going to see that later.
So let me run this.
So first, I need to build my index.
You build the index once, and
then we need to start to use it.
Let's see Here.
So here I have some queries
which are run through.
So each query, it have the tools that
must answer that question because
this is a demo and we want to know if
the agent is doing good or doing bad.
So let me run this.
And this is some helper function that
I built to capture which tool the agent
called and how many tokens it used.
Because with Trance, we have a native
feature that allows us to know how
many tokens I spent in this invocation.
With only this line I
can know that question.
So resolve metrics and accumulate
usage, I can know how many tokens
this this invocation is using.
So let me run this again And let's go.
So first we have the traditional approach.
It's the normal agent that we know.
So the agent get all the
29 tools on every query.
And let's see.
Let's run.
First, let me show you how you
can build an agent using strands.
So we have the agent, we have the tools,
all the tools in the system prompt.
You are a travel assistant.
Use the correct tools
to answer the question.
A super dummy agent.
And here the model.
Here the model.
You can swap the model only
changing this line, and that's it.
And this single
line build the agent loop.
And here we are going to… This is the
helper function to see how many tokens
we are spending in this invocation.
So here we have the first question,
search for something in Paris, and it
spent two thousand tokens in this single
invocation with this simple, super simple
question because we send all the 29 tools.
And I don't know if you remember,
but my tools was super simple
with a super simple description.
And the accuracy is not the best
first because the description
inside the tool aren't the best.
And then let's use the semantic approach.
Here, as I mentioned at the
beginning, I'm using the search tool.
So I send the query first to
that little tool, and it's going
to return the three candidate,
candidates to answer my question.
So then when I have this, I
put these tools information
inside my tool, inside my agent.
And it's the same, it's
the same invocation.
But every time that I run this
simple form, I want to swap
the tools inside the agent.
But it's not swap because every time that
I build this agent, I created a new agent
to answer this question And let me run.
For the first one, I have a-
almost four thousand tokens.
I don't know if you remember, but for
the first one is, oof, a lot, right?
A lot different between that.
And let's see.
The accuracy, I think, is going
to be similar because this
is not the, the tools is…
The description inside the tool doesn't
help us a lot to have a better accuracy.
A lot different.
Come on, this only spend almost two
thousand tokens, is a lot different.
So here we have the another test because
I don't know if you noticed, but the first
test, I create a new agent per query.
So every time that I invoke
the a- that I send a query, I'm
sending this query to a new agent.
So this is great for benchmarking,
but in production, you are
going to lose the conversation.
You need the conversation
history inside each invocation.
So here is where we are going to
use something powerful inside the
Strands agent, and it's the swap tool.
The little application that I
going to show you right now.
Here in the register,
we have the swap tool.
So with swap tool, we clear the register
and register only the three new tools.
So every time that we send a new prompt
to this agent, we don't need to create a
new agent with new tools because we can
swap this tool using the tool register
that is a feature inside Strands.
And let me go back here.
So with… We are doing the same thing.
With in the first query, we
send the query to the tool.
We have the tools.
We swap.
We're using the swap tools to put
the new tools inside the agent.
If you notice, I don't ev- I
don't invoke the agent inside.
I don't create the agent inside the for.
I create the agent out the for.
So my-- I first create the
agent, and then I start to send
the query inside the agent.
So every time that I send it a new
query, I haven't my memory, the agent
inside the memory, the chat history,
everything, and the only thing that I'm
doing here is swap the tool and sending
the new query So this is an some stuff to
measure the tokens and helper function.
So one thing here, every time
that we are invoking this agent,
we are sending the chat history.
So the tokens amount is going to
be bigger and bigger, but it's
not going to be bigger and bigger
because I'm sending more tokens.
It's bigger because I'm sending the chat's
history i-inside this new invocation,
and I only sending the inside the con-
the new context, I'm sending the tools
that this agent is going to need And of
course, I send you the, the, the last
tools that I was using before, but I never
send twenty-nine tools in one invocation.
And yeah, the accuracy is better.
But this is my agent here.
So here, let me show you a
final comparison against the ground truth.
So let me run this line.
There is a bunch of information
para- that I want to show you here.
So the, the token saving is a
pers… you can see here the
por… the token saving here.
And it's a lot.
I think the best thing
here is the token saving.
But the accuracy, you need to work in this
demo, the accuracy is not the best because
I remember let me remember that the,
the tools are super dummy with a super
general description, so it's not the best.
And here this is another
breakdown that you can use to
I don't know, to evaluate this.
And I don't know if you noticed, but
all this is using a local files index.
It's not the best solution for a demo.
So let me go to something
that I want to show you here.
Pa. Oh, wait, the, the first one.
This one.
So all this run in a files index is
perfect to learning and prototype.
But in production, you don't want to build
and maintain your own vector index, right?
So we have Amazon Bedrock, a Agent
Core Gateway that is a managed
service that enable you a semantic
search without build anything.
So it's like a API invocation that you
can integrate in your agentic application.
And of course, you need
the AWS credentials.
So you… It's like a MCP that you
can integrate in a API invocation.
And you re- you register… is you
build a register inside that, that
MCP, that a- that gateway, so you
can have the, your tools in Lambda
function, in a external code.
In a MCP, you can register
MCP there as well.
So every time that you invoke
your agent, it's the same.
You're going to send the
query to Agent Core Gateway.
It's going to search the best
tool for you, and it's going to
retrieve the best tool that you
can use to answer that question.
Tools and MCP And that's a thing.
And let me show you.
In this report that I'm going
to share with you, you have all
the architecture to create your
agentic gateway semantic search.
We only are infrastructure as a code.
I put everything there, and you
have infrastructure as a code.
If you don't know anything about
LangWS, I put information there.
So if you want to learn,
everything is there.
And come on, you can use
your assistance as well.
So and here five point that
I want to share with you.
Fewer tools before the model
with FAISS and embedding.
Because this is a, a FAISS application,
but this is a vector search.
So you need to build the embedding
first and then send that embedding to
do the search in your vector store.
Second, fewer tools cuts
both costs and error at once.
So I don't have to say
anything more about that.
Three, measure against ground
truth, not by eyes, and check
what are the correct tools.
It's research top three.
So please build a con-- a good
context inside your tools, so
you are going to build a better
vector search for that tools.
Four, swap tools per turns without
losing the conversation with swap tools.
This is something that I built here, but
it's going to depends of your framework.
If you are using LangChain or La-
LangGraph you need to search how you
can build that with that framework.
And in production, agent call gateway
does the semantic search for you.
You don't need to choose
a embedding model.
It's going to do everything for you.
And all the resource as here, but let me
share with you a QR code Here is better.
So please scan.
There is all my blogs and is
all the resources right there.
And thank you, and see
you in our next event